[Dr. Yoo] We combined our most practical
and effective tips for fresher breath,
and we did some research to
see what else people are doing.
[Jack] And at the end...
if you still can't get fresh breath,
there might be something else going on.
- This is a popular topic
for obvious reasons.
Fresh breath is something
that we all want to have.
- Sexy.
- It's sexy.
Oral hygiene's sexy.
So not only that,
a lot of these tips improve
your oral health in general.
- Yeah.
- And we'll talk
about conditions in your mouth
that can contribute to
halitosis or bad breath,
but also decay, gum disease,
and other systemic issues.
Routine or tip number seven.
- Is going to be drinking
less alcohol or coffee.
Why is that?
- Man, do you think you can do that?
(Jack clearing throat)
- We just finished
our coffee before we start filming, man.
- What is in our beloved coffee
that is promoting bad breath?
- So what caffeine can do
is give you the dry mouth.
You don't have as much saliva
moving around your mouth
and washing away all of the debris,
food, and bacteria.
And then also,
coffee can make you have bad breath
because it actually contains sulfur,
during the roasting of the beans.
What about alcohol,
does it do the same thing?
- Alcohol does something similar
in that it dries out your mouth.
The alcohol is also
converted into acetic acid,
which has a smell itself.
(Dr. John chuckling)
We're not saying
that you can't enjoy
it on your date night,
but, if you're experiencing
bad breath after drinking,
you'll know why.
So Jack,
less alcohol, do you think you can do that
for your next date night?
- Honestly, if you drink enough drinks,
then you won't care.
(Jack laughing)
(Dr. John chuckling)
- Not a pro tip.
Don't listen to him.
- Just kidding. Just kidding.
Just kidding.
- Drink in moderation
or drink less.
Okay, so the next tip,
number six, what are salivary stimulants?
This sounds crazy.
- Okay.
(Jack laughing)
So it's in the definition,
but something that will induce you
to create more saliva.
(water splashing)
- Okay.
- I'm trying to say it in a different way
than stimulating saliva, essentially.
- Got it, so we got some stuff here.
I use some of these things, actually.
I always have a pack of sugar-free gum.
- Yeah.
- That I chew after meals,
even after my coffee.
- Jack, are there any things that you like
to use on a daily basis?
- I like to use xylitol,
xylitol mints, xylitol gum.
- Right.
What is xylitol? Can you explain?
- Yeah, so xylitol is a sugar alcohol
that is non-cariogenic,
which means that it
doesn't create cavities.
(Dr. John: mmm)
- So there is such a thing?
- There is, a lot of times
when patients have a dry mouth,
it's really beneficial for them
to pop in a xylitol gum
right after they eat
to wash away the debris,
or before they fall asleep
and they have dry mouth,
to pop in a xylitol mint
that slowly releases
during the first half an hour,
an hour that they're sleeping.
- Dry mouth can promote many problems,
including bad breath.
Let's go to the next.
- Oh, oh, oh.
- Number five.
- Oh, we're back on John's favorite.
- My favorite?
- Tongue scraping.
- I think you're known for this.
(TV beeping)
So this step,
most people don't do it.
- You should do it.
- Yeah, you should do it.
It is really important that
you stick it as far back
as you can into your
throat without gagging.
And oftentimes I will gag.
(dramatic horn blowing)
(Jack laughing)
Because it means I'm
doing a really good job.
- You don't have to gag.
- You don't have to but
(TV beeping)
- For your knowledge
and entertainment, I'm
going to demonstrate on Jack
how to properly tongue scrape.
(Jack chuckling)
Stick this as far back
into your throat and scrape forward.
(Jack groaning)
Oh, that's disgusting.
(Jack gagging)
(Dr. John laughing)
- We're done with that
and now we can show, so.
(laughing)
- That's disgusting.
- Yeah, it's disgusting.
Oral hygiene is not always
the most sexy thing.
No actually cut that.
Oral hygiene is sexy.
Oral hygiene is totally sexy.
- Is sexy, okay.
When do you like to tongue scrape?
- Every hour. Every day.
(Jack chuckling)
- You're like Jungkook.
(Jack laughing)
Seven days a week.
All jokes aside,
it's really important to tongue scrape.
It's often forgotten in people's routine.
There's a lot of crap
that sits on your tongue.
If you think it's gross
that you just saw that,
imagine that back in your mouth.
- Imagine that in other people's mouths.
Imagine you kissing someone
that doesn't tongue scrape
and now you have their that in your mouth.
(Dr. John laughing)
- Their that?
(Jack laughing)
- Yeah.
- Perfect. Perfect.
You nailed it, man.
Let's go to the next one.
- So, routine tip number four.
And honestly, when we were doing research
on creating this video,
we didn't actually know this one,
and that is eating foods that
contain sulfur compounds.
- There are very obvious
foods that contain sulfur,
you know, your eggs.
Some people know that the onions
and garlic also contain that.
Cauliflower contains sulfur, correct?
- Yeah, even cabbage.
- I'm not saying that
you have to avoid these
to have fresher breath but.
(Dr. John sighing)
(knife chopping through onion)
I don't wanna eat that.
- I let you put in metal down my throat.
The least you can do is take a--
- Oh my gosh.
- Come on, take a big bite of that.
(Dr. John crunching through onion)
I'll do it too, man.
- Oh, gosh.
- Hey if you jump, I jump.
(Jack crunching through onion)
(Dr. John laughing)
So why do sulfur-containing
compounds smell bad?
- I think most people know
what sulfur smells like.
- Oh, okay.
- It's the egg odor.
- Okay, and we're not saying
to remove these foods from your diet.
We still are avid vegetable eaters.
- Lovers.
Second, after chicken breast.
- We're fully dedicated to data.
We're gonna test our breath now, blow.
(Dr. John blowing deeply)
- Oh, it only gave me a two
out of four.
- Two out of four.
- Dude, if this is two out of four,
what's a four out of four, man?
You gotta eat garbage?
(Dr. John laughing)
(Jack laughing)
I'm not doing that, man.
Routine tip number three.
This might be one of
the most important ones.
- Yep.
- It's very simple.
You can do it multiple times a day.
- It's just drinking water,
drinking more water after your meals,
after a snack,
just throughout the day.
- Or rinsing your mouth with
non-alcoholic mouth rinse.
- So this is TheraBreath.
I think it freshens my breath,
- Yeah.
(Dr. John exhaling)
and it's healthier for
your oral cavity as well.
Because after a meal,
oftentimes your mouth will be acidic,
and will restore your pH
back to normal levels.
Routine tip number two.
- This is honestly getting
more and more important too.
All these tips are important,
but this one is really important.
Going to your dentist for a checkup,
because a lot of times
they will be the ones
that are discovering
decay or perio disease,
which is like gum disease.
If you have caries or gum disease,
it's pretty much like decay in your mouth
and it smells foul.
- Even if you don't have decay,
there are also things that
your dentist can discover,
such as food traps.
- That's right, yeah.
- Can you explain what food traps are?
- I'll give an example of food trap.
Let's say you have a patient, two crowns.
The crowns are over contoured,
so it's pushing the gum
between the two teeth, down.
Now, that will leave a space,
a gap between the gum and the two crowns.
(Dr. John laughing)
- This is intense.
- Now, when you eat,
'cause I've seen it.
I've seen it.
I saw it last week.
Not only can it cause bad breath,
it can hurt 'cause it's
putting pressure on your gums.
And the moment you've
all been waiting for,
our final number one tip is a combination
of different things, John?
- Acid reflux, GERD,
tonsil stones.
There are a number of reasons
why your bad breath may be persistent,
even with impeccable hygiene and care.
- So why are these conditions
affecting your breath?
- Think of this as one long
tube.
And if you have problems arising here,
acid reflux, indigestion,
even from up here,
the back of your throat
where the tonsil stones are,
you can produce odors
not coming from here,
but the rest of your digestive tract.
- Oh, I also seen some crazy videos
of tonsil stones being removed.
It's like pimple popping on crack.
(Dr. John laughing)
It's like next level pimple popping.
These stones can get huge.
- So these stones are made up of bacteria.
These are clumps,
clusters of debris, bacteria.
They sit on the,
what's called tonsillar crypts.
So when you remove it,
you can fix your bad breath immediately.
- Right, imagine having
like a week's worth of food.
- More than a week, dude.
- Yeah.
- Some of these accumulate over months,
years, man.
- So bad.
- Your dentist can find
these tonsil stones.
- They're good at hide and seek.
(Dr. John laughing)
- Your dentist is a good seeker.
(Jack exclaiming)
- Oh, okay.
So yes, some of these
are medical conditions
that you can't fix with your routine,
but there are some things that you can do
on a daily basis to
help keep this healthy.
- Yeah, such as not overeating,
drinking less alcohol.
- Eating the right foods.
- Yeah,
eating the right foods.
And finally..
- Oral hygiene is sexy.
(Jack laughing)
(Dr. John laughing)